erinpavlina.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy - Erin Pavlina

#### Who we are

This privacy notice explains how we collect and process your personal data on the web site ErinPavlina.com

We don’t share or use your data except as described in this Privacy Notice.

The Data Controller for GDPR purposes is Erin Pavlina.

#### Summary

  * We’re not in the data collecting business 
  * If we collect data about you it is because you ask us to 
  * We look after that data as best we can 
  * We don’t give it to other people to use 
  * We delete it as soon as we can 

#### The data we collect and why

When you order a reading from us you provide us your contact details, photo, and any other information you provide in order to fulfill your request. Our GDPR lawful grounds of processing is “Contract.”

When you order a product from us you provide your contact details, as well as your payment information which is processed by our payment provider. Our GDPR lawful grounds of processing is “Contract.”

If you communicate with us via email, social media etc. we process this data for the purposes of communicating with you, and for our own record keeping. Our GDPR lawful grounds of processing is “Contract” and in some cases “Legitimate Interest.”

We do not collect or process any data defined as “Sensitive Data” under the EU GDPR. 

All billing information is processed directly by our payment processor and is not stored by us. 

#### Marketing communications

We have a mailing list you can join to receive notification of new articles, offers, etc. You may unsubscribe from this at any time by following the instructions in every email. 

We do not share your details with any third party for marketing purposes. 

#### Where we process your data

We use a variety of different services to run our business, and they store your data in different countries. 

In all cases we have confirmed our suppliers are GDPR compliant and if they are not storing your data in the EEA, then either the EU-US Privacy Shield or other controls are in place. 

Types of services we use are:

  * Email/Calendar 
  * Calendar booking system 
  * Online store 
  * Payment processor 
  * Mailing list provider 

#### Data security

We have put in measures to safeguard your data; we have also required those who work for us to have similar safeguards and to process your data only on our instructions and keep it confidential. 

#### Data retention

We keep your data for only as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which collected it, including our need to satisfy legal, accounting, and reporting requirements. 

#### Your legal rights

You can contact us ([www.erinpavlina.com/contact-erin-pavlina](https://www.erinpavlina.com/contact-erin-pavlina)) to request what data we have about you, to ask us to erase applicable data, correct mistakes etc. When you make a Data Subject Access Request we will ask you for additional information to confirm your identity. 

#### Third party links

In our website we often link to other websites, different plugins etc. This site and its owner(s) are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

#### Cookies

All websites use cookies, but some cookies are helpful cookies which make the site work, and some are a bit sinister and can be used stalk you. If you want to control what cookies your web browser accepts, you can do this in your browser settings. 

We don’t use any of the really invasive services which track you around the web, and our site respects Do Not Track. 

As with most websites, we use Google Analytics to gather website statistics which will place a cookie in your browser. 

#### Logging

Whenever there is a request to our web site, there’s a log of the IP address and date stored in a log file. We use this information to operate the website and allow us to detect cyber attacks. 

#### Changes to this Privacy Notice

If we make changes to this Privacy Notice, we’ll update this web page.
